Guide to the Durham Hosiery Mills Records, 1887-1962 and undated RL.11502
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Hosiery Mills records
1887-1962 and undated
1895-1922
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Hosiery Mills (Durham, N.C.)
RL.11502
45.9 Linear Feet 5,477 items
Collection comprises letters, bills, time books, ledgers, check stubs, inventories, broadsides, stock certificates, dye house records, and other materials. The bulk of the letters, 1895-1897, date to George M. Graham's service as secretary and treasurer of the Durham Hosiery Company, as do many of the volumes. Topics include machinery and supplies purchased from firms in the North, newly organized textile mills in the South, the installation and repair of machinery, the sale of hosiery, the purchase of yarn, wages offered, and the hiring of laborers.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Records and Volumes.
Biographical / Historical
The Durham Hosiery Mills was incorporated in 1898, following the merger of the Durham Hosiery Company, founded 1895, and the Golden Belt Hosiery Company. The firm operated at least seven mills, including facilities at High Point and Carrboro. In 1969 the company relocated to a new plant in Franklin County, N.C.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Hosiery Mills records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1944 and 1969 and transfer in 1985.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises records, letters, bills, time books, ledgers, check stubs, inventories, broadsides, stock certificates, dye house records, letterbooks, accounts of loopers, cash books, and express books. The bulk of the letters, 1895-1897, date to George M. Graham's service as secretary and treasurer of the Durham Hosiery Company, as do many of the volumes. Topics include machinery and supplies purchased from firms in the North, newly organized textile mills in the South, the installation and repair of machinery, the sale of hosiery, the purchase of yarn, wages offered, and the hiring of laborers. Southern textile mills mentioned include the Raleigh Cotton Mills, the Eden Park Cotton Mill of Atlanta, Ga., the McCall Manufacturing Co. of McCall, S.C., the Eno Cotton Mills of Hillsboro, N.C.; the Mayo Mills of Mayodan, N.C., the Clover Cotton Manfacturing Co. of Clover, S.C., and the Kerr Thread Company of Atlanta, Ga.
Cotton textile industry -- North Carolina; Industries -- North Carolina -- Carrboro; Industries -- North Carolina -- Durham; Industries -- North Carolina -- High Point; Industries -- North Carolina; Textile industry -- North Carolina; Textile industry -- Southern States; Textile machinery.; Durham (N.C.) -- History; Durham Hosiery Mills (Durham, N.C.); Durham Hosiery Mills (Durham, N.C.) -- History; Graham, George M.
- Records, 1887-1962 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  The Records Series comprises letters, bills, returned checks, broadsides, and other materials. The bulk of the letters, 1895-1897, date to George M. Graham’s service as secretary and treasurer of the Durham Hosiery Company. Topics include machinery and supplies purchased from firms in the North, newly organized textile mills in the South, the installation and repair of machinery, the sale of hosiery, the purchase of yarn, wages offered, and the hiring of laborers.
  - 1887-1893, 1895 January-December (Box 1)
  - 1896 January-May (Box 2)
  - 1896 June-October (Box 3)
  - 1896 November-1897 February (Box 4)
  - 1897 March-April (Box 5)
  - 1897 May-June (Box 6)
  - 1897 July-August (Box 7)
  - 1897 September-October (Box 8)
  - 1897 January-April Cancelled checks (Box 8)
  - 1897 May-December Cancelled checks (Box 9)
  - 1897 November-December, 1898-1899 (Box 9)
  - 1917-1962 and undated (Box 10)
- Volumes, 1895-1922 and undated
  Arrangement
  Arranged by company, mill, then type of ledger.
  The Volumes Series contains primarily the financial records of the company, although there are also time books, check stubs, inventories, stock certificates, letter books, and dye house records. Many items date to George M. Graham’s service as secretary and treasurer of the Durham Hosiery Company.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Account of Loopers (Durham, N.C.), undated; 80 pages 16x10 cm. (Volume 3)
    Contains employee records, by week.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Account Book (Durham, N.C), 1896; 26 pages 15x9 cm (Volume 4)
    Includes records by day of dozens knit, broken down by size of gauge (?). Also, a 2-page record of good and poor work by machines, with numbers of pieces and needles.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Check Stubs (Durham, N.C.), 1897; 50 pages 15x13 cm. (Volume 5)
    Records of checks and deposits, as well as amounts overdrawn and balances.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Cash Book (Durham, N.C.), 1895-1896; 140 pages 37x20 cm. (Volume 6)
    Volume tracks accounts for yar, machinery, dyeing, expenses, and labor, along with balances within respective banks.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Cash Book (Durham, N.C.), 1897-1898; 105 pages 37x21 cm. (Volume 7)
    Volume primarily tracks expenses, labor, and dyeing, with payments for individuals and companies, along with balances.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Express Book from Southern Express Company (Durham, N.C.), 1896-1897; 100 pages 14x20 cm. (Volume 8)
    Includes bills of lading for Durham Hosiery Mills, often with amounts collected.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Inventory (Durham, N.C.), 1898; 9 pages 35x20 cm (Volume 9)
    Items mentioned include yarn, boxes, miscellaneous items, stamps and findings, and mayoparts (?).
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Inventory of Supplies, etc. (Durham, N.C.), undated; 16 pages 30x13 cm. (Volume 10)
    Inlcudes amounts knitted, looped, dyed, pressed, fleeced, hemmed, mated, bundled, boxed, and seconds, along with amount of yarn and numbers of boxes. There ia an inventory of supplies and items in the knitting room.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Journal (Durham, N.C.), 1895-1897; 403 pages 41x24 cm. (Volume 12)
    Volume dates from the founding of the Durham Hosiery Company. There are entries for machinery, fuel, yarn, expenses, findings, dyeing, salaries, and labor, along with entries for companies and individuals.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Ledger (Durham, N.C.), 1897-1898; 398 pages 41x24 cm (Volume 11)
    Includes entries for stock and various company accounts, as well as entries for other companies, merchandise, freight, and individuals.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Letter Book (Durham, N.C.), 1895-1896; 503 pages 30x24 cm. (Volume 13)
    Handwritten letterbook. Topics include orders, payment of accounts, as well as requests for quotes and samples. Includes index.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Letter Book (Durham, N.C.), 1896-1897; 500 pages 30x 24 cm. (Volume 14)
    Handwritten letters. Topics include orders, payment of accounts, machinery, and requests for quotes. Includes index. Many of the letters are too faint to read because of the passage of time and water damage to the volume.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Letter Book (Durham, N.C.), 1897; 501 pages 31x24 cm. (Volume 15)
    Handwritten letters. Topics include shipping and receiving of cases, orders for machinery and yarn, sales accounts and statements, and hiring. Includes index.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Letter Book (Durham, N.C.), 1897; 496 pages 30x24 cm. (Volume 16)
    Handwritten letters. Topics include bills, orders and payment, machinery, supplies, and shipping and receiving. Includes index.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Record Book (Durham, N.C.), undated; 14 pages 17x10 cm. (Volume 17)
    Records for cases of hosiery, including date packed, weight, color, size, and quantity.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Records of Dye House (Durham, N.C.), 1897-1898; 100 pages 17x10 cm. (Volume 18)
    Includes records for hosiery, with date, case, how many dozens, size, style, and weight, then tracks shipments to dye houses according to weight, color, size, and quantity.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Stock Certificates and Records (Durham, N.C.), 1895-1897; 400 pages 21x34 cm. (Volume 19)
    Stock shares worth $100 each. Only 40 of the certificates were issued; a few of these were voided.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Time Book (Durham, N.C.), 1896-1897; 140 pages 17x10 cm. (Volume 20)
    Volume holds preprinted pages that contain a table of wages. There are weekly time records for employees, including pay rates per day.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Time Book (Durham, N.C.), 1897-1898; 88 pages 19x11 cm. (Volume 21)
    Volume contains weekly time records for employees, organized by room in the mill, with notes on pay rate per day.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Time Book (Durham, N.C.), 1898; 11 pages 17x10 cm. (Volume 22)
    Volume contains preprinted pages with tables of wages by the day. There are weekly time records for employees, organized by room in the mill, with rate of pay.
  - Durham Hosiery Company: Time Book (Durham, N.C.), undated; 64 pages 15x9 cm. (Volume 23)
    Volume contains weekly time records for employees with amount of "good work" and rate of pay.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 General Ledger, No. 1, (High Point, N.C.), 1906-1916; 253 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 24)
    Volume contains accounts receivable, along with those for salaries, dye material, stamps, merchandise, boxing, etc.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 General Ledger, No. 2 (High Point, N.C.), 1917-1922; 246 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 25)
    Volume contains entries for stock, repairs, findings, wrapping materials, expenses, supplies, labor, office supplies, fuel, freight, and boxing, among others.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 Journal, No. 1 (High Point, N.C.), 1907-1915; 300 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 26)
    Volume contains accounts payable and receivable, with entries for repairs, findings, expenses, labor, dye, fuel, office supplies, etc.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 Journal, No. 2 (High Point, N.C.), 1915-1920; 304 pages 47x31 cm (Volume 27)
    Volume contains accounts receivable and payable, with entries in general and sales ledgers. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented, as are offices in other cities.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 Voucher Record, No. 1 (High Point, N.C.), 1907-1914; 524 pages 48x45 cm (Volume 28)
    Volume contains entries for utilities, autos, salaries, loopers, parts and supplies, yarn, and traveling expenses, among others.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 Voucher Record, No. 2 (High Point, N.C.), 1914-1919; 492 pages 48x45 cm (Volume 29)
    Volume contains entries for yarn, repairs, payroll and salaries, and parts, among others. Payments regarding "long and faithful service" are noted in Jan. 1917. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 3 Voucher Record, No. 3 (High Point, N.C.), 1919-1922; 262 pages 50x45 cm (Volume 30)
    Volume contains entries for yarn, repairs, salaries and payroll, utilities, dye, insurance, fuel, and office supplies, among others. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 General Ledger, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1909-1916; 280 pages 46x32 cm (Volume 31)
    Volume contains entries for repairs, findings, expenses, labor, engine and yard, salaries, waste, discount on goods bought, etc. Includes entries for barbeque.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 General Ledger, No. 2 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1917-1922; 300 pages 46x32 cm (Volume 32)
    Volume contains entries for stocks, repairs, findings, expenses, labor, engine and yard, office supplies, and fuel, among others. There is a table of contents.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 Journal, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1909-1915; 280 pages 46x32 cm (Volume 33)
    Volume contains accounts receivable and payable, with entries for sales ledger and general ledger.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 Journal, No. 2 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1915-1918; 292 pages 48x44 cm (Volume 34)
    Volume contains accounts receivable and payable, with entries for sales ledger and general ledger. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 Journal, No. 3 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1918-1922; 299 pages 46x32 cm (Volume 35)
    Volume contains accounts receivable and payable, with individuals and companies present. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 Voucher Record, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1909-1918; 480 pages 48x44 cm (Volume 36)
    Volume contains accounts for payroll, freight, machinery and parts, repairs, utilities, and yarn, among others. There are other Durham Hosiery Mills represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 4 Voucher Record, No. 2 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1918-1922; 256 pages 47x45 cm (Volume 37)
    Includes vouchers for payroll, parts, supplies, repairs, taxes, utilities, etc. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 6 General Ledger, No.1 (Durham, N.C.), 1914-1921; 289 pages 46x32 cm (Volume 38)
    Volume contains a wide variety of accounts, including stocks, repairs, and renewals, findings, expenses, office supplies, fuel, freight, boxing, storage, machinery and fixtures, building and plant, cotton, salaries, insurance, waste, and processes by room in mill, among others.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 6 Journal, No. 1 (Durham, N.C.), 1914-1921; 266 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 39)
    Volume contains accounts receivable and payable, with entries for profit and loss, sales and general ledger. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented. Laid into the volume is an empty "Statement of Income and Expenses for Six Months."
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 6 Voucher Record, No. 1 (Durham, N.C.), 1915-1918; 246 pages 49x45 cm (Volume 40)
    Volume contains entries for salary and payroll, fuel, waste, supplies, parts, yarn, and cotton, among others. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 6 Voucher Record, No. 2 (Durham, N.C.), 1918-1920; 172 pages 49x45 cm (Volume 41)
    Volume contains entries for painting the mill, salaries, supplies, frieght, waste, repairs, etc. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 7 General Ledger, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1913-1922; 303 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 42)
    Volume contains a wide variety of accounts, including stocks, repairs, and renewals, findings, expenses, office supplies, fuel, freight, boxing, storage, machinery and fixtures, building and plant, cotton, salaries, insurance, waste, and processes by room in mill, among others. Contains a table of contents on the inside front cover.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 7 Journal, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1913-1921; 299 pages 47x32 cm (Volume 43)
    Volume contains accounts payable and receivable, showing profits and losses. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. 7 Voucher Record, No. 1 (Carrboro, N.C.), 1913-1922; 380 pages 48x45 cm (Volume 44)
    Volume contains entries for salary and payrool, supplies, machinery and parts, repairs, freight, and insurance, among others. Other Durham Hosiery Mills are represented.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Employee Representative Plan, Minutes of Representatives (Durham, N.C.), 1920-1921; 86 pages 22x19 cm (Box 11, Volume 1)
    Typewritten minutes. This body, along with the Senate, appears to have regulated working conditions at the Durham Hosiery Mills by establishing mill policies and settling disputes.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Employees Representative Plan, Minutes of Senate (Durham, N.C.), 1919-1921; 146 pages 22x19 cm (Box 11, Volume 2)
    Typewritten minutes. This body, along with the Representatives, appears to have regulated working conditions at the Durham Hosiery Mills by establishing mill policies and settling disputes.
  - Durham Hosiery Mills: Mill No. ? (Orders Received Ledger), 1910-1913; 499 pages 41x39 cm (Volume 45)
    Title of volume not provided by the company, but assigned at cataloging. Orders are organized by company and date, with rush orders indicated.